Instructor: So during the next few sections,
we're gonna be building our very own
Microsoft Excel spreadsheet.
We're gonna start out with just a completely blank worksheet
and we're gonna build up a monthly budget spreadsheet.
We're gonna start out, just simple, take it step by step.
We're gonna do things like enter labels
like our column and our row labels.
We're gonna enter some numeric values in there
representing our dollar amounts, our currency values
the hard earned money that we're spending each
and every month on all of our bills.
We'll talk about building calculations so we can get things
like totals for each month or each bill.
I'll talk about some other types of calculations as well.
And we're gonna do some formatting.
We're gonna make it look super awesome
but we're gonna start from complete scratch.
So our first step, we've gotta open up a new
Excel document and we're gonna start to put some
labels or headers into our spreadsheets.
So here we go.
So I'm back into the Excel interface and I'm looking
at the new section of the backstage view or of the file tab.
So now inside of here, I'm gonna go ahead
and grab blank workbook and I'll give that a double click.
All right, here we are. We've done this once before.
We've opened up a new blank Excel document and here we are.
Now I'm on office 365.
I subscribe to the monthly subscription
through Microsoft to get access
to the office applications, Excel, Word,
PowerPoint and so on.
Now, occasionally, and I just really want to
give you a heads up, if you're also a part
of the Office 365 subscription, whether you get that
through a personal edition or something through work
Microsoft likes to push out updates.
Now as of this recording, it is February of 2019.
This is our current release of Microsoft Excel.
Now when you open it up
your interface might look a little bit different
'cause Microsoft pushes out updates.
So nothing big.
I've been teaching Excel for years now
and I teach it virtually exactly the same way.
I've been teaching ever since the early,
early editions of Microsoft Excel 2000 back in 95,
Excel's been Excel for years.
Of course, Microsoft has introduced new features
and whatnot, and we'll get into those new features.
And I wanna, I wanna talk about all the bells and whistles
that Microsoft adds to additional versions
but it's still underlying, it's still Excel.
Now, once again, if you are on the office 365
you may occasionally when you first launch up Excel,
you may get a yellow bar at the top of your screen saying.
"Hey Microsoft's got some updates ready for you.
Do you want to go ahead and update?"
And they'll give you a button right there to build update.
I'm not getting it right now.
And we may see it at some point within this course
as I close and I reopen Excel
and Microsoft may be pushing out updates
but just keep an eye on that inside of your own interface.
Updates are great.
Microsoft is fixing things, creating new features for you.
It's huge.
So, alright, here we are.
So typically we start out inside of cell A1
within our new worksheet and there I set A1,
what better place to put a title?
So I'm gonna go ahead and put a title here.
I'll call this monthly budget.
This is gonna be our monthly budget spreadsheet.
And again, I'm just inside of column A, row one
type that value in.
I'm gonna hit my enter key on my keyboard.
That'll hop me out of that cell.
All right, so there's my title.
We'll worry about making that fancy looking colors
and bold and all that stuff. We'll do that later on.
For now, we're just gonna put some labels in there
and start to build the basic structure of our spreadsheet.
So I'm gonna drop down into cell A3
and I'm gonna create a column here that's gonna act
as the labels for all of the bills
that I have for each of the months.
So first thing I'm gonna put in here
is just a nice header, we'll just call it bills.
I'm gonna hit my enter key to drop down a cell again
and now I'm gonna create a list.
Nice little column here
of various bills that I have for each month.
Now you can copy me exactly if you liked you.
Hopefully you're following along with me, right?
You can copy the exact same stuff if you like
but I wanna encourage you, one of the base, best ways to
learn something new is not only participate in a course
like this and to learn, but to put it to practice.
So the sooner that you can start to put this
into your own real world scenarios
the better off you're gonna be.
And so think about what bills do you have, right?
So here, I'm just gonna make some stuff up.
I'm gonna say we got rent, we got phone
we got credit cards. Credit.
Make sure I spelled that right "Credit cards".
Hit my enter key drop down again.
Let's say we got food and let's do one more here.
I'm gonna say candy.
Gotta have candy, right?
Each and every month you got your bill for your candy.
All right, I'm gonna hit my enter key, I'll drop down.
Now that's good. I'm gonna call it good right there.
Of course, I've got more inside of there.
Maybe we wanna put car in there.
You got electricity, you got gas, you got garbage and water
you got this, that, and the other thing, right?
Whatever bills you have, right?
Let's go ahead and create a list there, and eventually we're
gonna start to put in the values for each of the
months that we're spending on these various bills.
Start to start to make you feel kind of bad where all your
your money's going, right?
Hopefully it's going to candy though, right?
All right, down below that, again,
I'm just gonna stop it there.
I'm gonna put in a total, eventually we're gonna
have a row here, right here that's gonna give us some totals
for the various months that will have for each of our bills.
All right, so these are our row headers, our row labels.
Let's go ahead and continue building the structure.
I'm gonna jump up into cell B3.
I'm just clicking up there and I'm gonna put some labels
up here for each of the months.
So as of recording right now, it is February of 2019
but I'm gonna go ahead and start this out at January.
So I'm just gonna type in Jan.
If you wanna type out January, feel free
you can do that as well.
I have a couple of Achilles heels of my own
as far as spelling's concerned.
My spelling is horrible.
My kids come home from school
and ask me how to spell something.
I open up word, Microsoft Word, and I type it in there.
Spell checker, right?
It's awesome.
So January, February, right?
I can never remember how to spell those two.
So I'm just gonna abbreviate.
I'll say Jan, I'm gonna hit my tab key just to hop
over to the right one cell.
I'll type in Feb tab and I'll type in Mar March.
I'm gonna hit my, actually
I'm gonna hit tab key one more time.
I'm gonna stop right there
for the months and keep it really simple.
If you'd like, you can continue going, right?
The more practice you get, the better.
You can go to April, May, June, July.
You can do whatever you like you want to inside of there.
You can start at whatever month you want.
Again, up to you.
But I'm gonna stop right there.
And I'm gonna put another total label.
Remember we've got this one, we got this guy down here.
Let's hit my enter key. Hop outta there.
We got that one right there 'cause eventually
we're gonna have some a row total here for each column.
But then I'm gonna have one here
'cause I want to do totals for each of the bills as well.
So this right here, this is kind of the basic structure
of a spreadsheet.
You've got row labels in this case bills
you've got column labels representing some type of date.
Now there's our basic structure, our labels
and these are just text values.
So if you're not following along with me
step by step right now, go ahead and pause the video.
Start to create the basic structure
the labels of your Excel monthly budget.
So get that part done, pause the video if you need to.
Once you're done, jump back in our next lecture.
We're gonna start to talk about entering numeric values
and putting some currency amounts inside
of these months for these bills.
So get that done.
We'll jump into the next section.